A Guide to the Papers of Servais and Terrill 1814-1847
Special Collections and University Archives, Patricia W. and J. Douglas Perry Library, Old Dominion University
Special Collections and University Archives, Patricia W. and J. Douglas Perry Library, Old Dominion University
Papers of Servais and Terrill 1814-1847
Special Collections and University Archives, Patricia W. and J. Douglas Perry Library, Old Dominion University
MG 22
1 document case
Administrative Information
Access
The collection is open to researchers without restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Kenneth Servais and Donald Terrill, June 1977
Biographical/Historical Information
The Bank of Chambersburg of Franklin, Pennsylvania was founded in 1809, and incorporated in 1814. It is the second bank in the Cumberland Valley. The bank building was built in 1829, and later destroyed in McCausland's raid on July 30, 1864.
After the building, and indeed much of the town, was burned, the bank temporarily conducted its business first in the home of D.L. Wunderlich on Second Street, and later in the lower room of the local Masonic Hall. In 1864, the bank received a new charter as the National Bank of Chambersburg.
Its Board Presidents have included: Joseph Culbertson, 1848-1858; William Heyser, 1858-1863; and William McClellan, 1863-1873, and others. Cashiers have included: James Lesley, 1845-1858; and George R. Messersmith, 1858-1881.
Scope and Content Information
The Servais and Terrill collection consists mostly of correspondence about banking and other financial transactions. Dates of the documents range from 1814 to 1847.
Arrangement
Arrangement is chronological.
Contents List
- Timothy Fuller (?) to Moody Trent (?) December 14, 1814 (Box-folder Box 1, Folder 1)
- A. Calhoun to E. Beatty January 5, 1835 (Box-folder Box 1, Folder 2)
- Bank of Chambersburg to E. Beatty January 25, 1838 (Box-folder Box 1, Folder 3)
- Bank of Chambersburg to E. Beatty January 27, 1838 (Box-folder Box 1, Folder 4)
- Bank of Chambersburg to E. Beatty May 5, 1838 (Box-folder Box 1, Folder 5)
- Bank of Chambersburg to E. Beatty July 5, 1838 (Box-folder Box 1, Folder 6)
- Bank of Chambersburg to E. Beatty July 16, 1838 (Box-folder Box 1, Folder 7)
- Bank of Chambersburg to E. Beatty August 13, 1838 (Box-folder Box 1, Folder 8)
- Bank of Chambersburg to E. Beatty October 1, 1838 (Box-folder Box 1, Folder 9)
- Bank of Metropolis to E. Beatty August 10, 1846 (Box-folder Box 1, Folder 10)
- Henry Dehuff (?) to Nathan Trotter & Co. Copper Merchants September 25, 1847 (Box-folder Box 1, Folder 11)